Oh, no!
What happened?
Mom!
No, no! Ricardo, no!
IF EVERYONE WAS MURDERED,
WHO WILL TELL THE STORY?
THE MURDERER?
No, no, no.
Oh, no!
What happened?
-Come here!
-Shut the door!
Dad!
Ricardo!
-No, no!
-No, Ricardo!
It's outside!
There it is.
Get it.
Careful with the lampshades, Ricardo!
That's enough.
Is it dead?
Is it done?
Poor thing.
We christened the house.
BARREDA: HUSBAND, FATHER, MURDERER
-Barreda.
-Barreda, please.
A photo over here, Barreda.
-Silence, please.
-Ricardo, look at the camera.
Good morning.
Let's proceed with the oral hearing
in the case against Mr. Ricardo Barreda.
Over here, Doctor.
Can the photographers
leave the room, please?
Barreda.
Can you dim the lights, please? Thank you.
On November 15, 1992,
in the house located on 809 48th Street
in La Plata,
its residents Gladys McDonald,
Cecilia and Adriana Barreda,
and Elena Arreche
received multiple gunshots
fired from a Victor Sarasqueta shotgun.
Barreda, what did you do that day
after you killed them?
Good morning, Barreda!
Good morning.
I'm sorry. He's looking for his friend.
Come on, boy.
Yes, I'll let you know when I walk him.
Say hi to Beba.
What did you do, Barreda?
I fucked up.
Leave it to me.
I'll handle it.
LIVE BAIT
WE HAVE SHAD
You've really made me wait for you, love.
Yeah, I've made you wait.
Miss.
Yes, tell me.
-May I have another one of these?
-Sure.
ROMA
PIZZA PLACE
No peeking.
-Wait, it won't play it.
-So?
-What's the surprise?
-There.
The boom box you wanted.
It's for all of us to share.
When you think about someone
Oh, I see.
It comes with a show.
Here, this is for you. Merry Christmas.
I made it myself.
When you are in the dark
That's nice.
I'm glad you like it.
When the morning comes
You can see the sky and the world
Hey! Will you come already?
Oh, wow!
I love it.
It's beautiful.
-This is great, Mom.
-Do you like it?
-That's the one you wanted.
-Yes.
It's beautiful.
They're high rise.
Will my butt fit in these?
-That remains to be seen.
-You're so mean.
Show Grandma. She pitched in.
I love it.
-Thanks, Dad.
-Thanks.
This is for you.
I didn't forget what you wanted.
You can't say I don't keep you in mind.
Thanks.
Okay, girls. I have presents.
Grandma's full of bags
from El Corte Inglés.
-This is for you, and this is for you.
-Is that what I think it is?
Maybe. Open it.
-Here, buy yourself something nice.
-Mom…
Come on, take it.
-I didn't get you anything.
-Buy yourself whatever you want.
Grandma!
Thanks, Mom.
I bought it where you told me.
The mannequin that was carrying it
commanded such authority
that I almost fell in love.
But I didn't buy you any cartridges.
-No.
-What?
It's for the best.
They say guns are loaded by the devil.
Customs was a mess. There was a long line.
But they saw I was an old lady
and let me go through.
I could have smuggled drugs.
-How much did you drink?
-What you gave me.
You haven't offered us anything yet, Mom.
-I love it.
-Can I change it?
-So nice.
-Yes.
No…
Ricardo, go check
if the circuit breakers tripped.
Police station. Good evening.
Hello. Some robbers broke into my house.
There are four bodies.
Are you okay?
Yes, I just got home and saw dead bodies.
-Let's go.
-This way.
Commissioner.
My God.
No signs of struggle.
She didn't try to defend herself.
-Gentlemen.
-Good evening, Commissioner.
Good evening, Commissioner.
Commissioner, come with me, please.
Upstairs.
Weird, isn't it?
They ransacked every room but this one.
Commissioner.
Who does that belong to?
It belonged to her.
Excuse me, Barreda.
-Can I address you informally?
-Yes.
You'll have to come with us
to the station.
-What for?
-It's a routine procedure.
We won't keep you long.
Gentlemen.
Imagine losing your whole family.
I can't believe it.
I took my dog out for a walk today
and everything seemed fine.
Make way, please.
My deepest condolences, Barreda.
How can you guarantee
this won't happen to me?
-Come on!
-These are too big for me.
-So?
-Yes.
-No, these shoes are too big.
-Try the pink ones.
-You can't get your diploma in flip-flops.
-I know, but I need low heels.
-Something a bit more comfortable.
-Yes.
This looks weird.
Yes, you need more boobs.
Look who's talking.
You're not exactly Cicciolina.
Hang on, I got it.
-Be careful. Poor thing.
-Yes.
Let's see…
Look at you. You're a bombshell.
No, I look ridiculous.
Gastón will laugh at me
if he sees me like this.
Did you tell Mom?
No, not yet.
Mommy!
There we go.
You can close your mouth now.
The worst part is over.
Did it hurt that much?
I won't forgive myself for that.
Do you know why?
Because if it hurts,
it means I failed as a dentist.
You know how your father gets.
Don't even think about telling him.
Okay, you're right.
Later, if things work out
between you and this guy,
we invite him over for some tea,
and you can introduce him formally.
-But she already invited him.
-Stop, Adriana.
-What?
-Are you two serious about each other?
Ceci.
Yes.
We're moving in together.
And you're telling me now?
I'm sorry.
Does he have a family?
Yes, he has a daughter.
He's great.
-Oh, no, Cecilia.
-We're serious, Mom.
What were you talking about?
You look so fancy, Grandma.
-Really?
-Yes.
-Do you like it?
Is that what you're wearing?
Yes. Why? I don't look good in it?
No, it's beautiful.
Almost…
There we go.
So, has anyone
ever treated you this nicely?
Spit in there.
What is it?
-We're ready.
-Wait for me outside.
Okay.
Family.
-Has anyone seen the keys?
-No, not me.
-Hello.
-Commissioner.
How does he look? Has he eaten?
No, but he's calm.
Bring him some food. Make conversation,
give him a little distraction.
MONZÓN
WORLD CHAMPION - NATIONAL IDOL
Help yourself.
-Thanks.
-No problem.
Excuse me.
Do you like the champ?
That was taken in 1970,
when he beat Benvenuti in Rome.
-Well, well, we have a fan.
-The number one fan.
-Did you ever meet him?
-I saw him a couple of times at Atenas.
Did you talk to him?
I must have asked him, "What's up, champ?"
"How are you doing?"
Unfortunately…
fame and his issues with women
took him on another path.
We'll have to see each other again.
You have to complete
the treatment in one week.
Don't give me that look.
It didn't hurt that much, did it?
No, don't touch it.
Apply some ice for the swelling
and don't do any workout.
None at all, okay?
Where's your purse?
Whatever you need, call me.
Or I'll call you.
-Thanks, Doctor.
-Of course.
The four of you are on time.
It's a miracle.
Don't start, Ricardo.
Mom, come here.
Don't you want to sit at the front?
Guys, you can leave now, please.
The Criminal Code.
I found a way to get you out of this.
We can cite psychiatric problems.
Psychiatric?
Look.
Read this.
"Section 34."
"It's not punishable
if during the incident,
the person could not control their actions
in case of alienation--"
But I didn't do anything.
You took
a criminology course recently, right?
At the bar association, remember?
How did you know that?
This is a small city.
Look, I won't turn you in,
but I need you to cooperate.
Let's do the following.
You'll tell me where you hid the gun,
and I'll tell you
who told me about the course.
If you cooperate and do as I say,
you'll get out of this one.
Where's the gun?
In Punta Lara.
I ran into Patricia Hernández
and I asked her about the wedding.
-If she was coming--
-One second.
-Can you lower the volume so I can hear?
-Yes, Dad.
Okay. Keep going.
-There's something fishy there.
-Yes.
Yes, I think she has
a problem with her father.
He has a betting problem.
-A gambling issue?
-That's awful.
Either way, you can't torment your family
because of your addiction.
Carlos paid good money
to fix her wife's teeth.
That fat hag has a fortune in her mouth.
Come on, Ricardo.
No wonder his wife had these huge bags
under her eyes
when I ran into her at Dardo Rocha
for the Berni exhibition.
Well, she has to explain herself
to everyone all the time…
-Yes, poor her.
-All because of her stupid husband.
Okay, Mom.
Come on, Mom.
Ricardo, please behave today.
Why? What did I do?
It's Ceci's night.
How are you?
-Hi.
-Quiet, please.
Please take your seats.
-Sit down.
-But there's no seat for Ricardo.
In a few moments, you'll have time
to talk among yourselves.
-Further in.
-Wait, Barreda.
-Further in. I'll tell him.
-No, wait, Barreda.
Suárez, 45 degrees from here.
There.
Nothing to see here. Step away, please.
Bingo!
Cuff him.
-This way.
-Turn around.
Julio! What are they doing?
Didn't we have a deal?
What are you doing?
-Julio!
-Calm down, Barreda. Just cooperate.
"Cooperate"? We had an agreement.
Hey!
We found the gun, Barreda. You're screwed.
-Take him away.
-For fuck's sake. Don't push me.
You have no word of honor, you scoundrel.
It's a huge honor for all of us here
to celebrate--
-Where do I sit?
-Find a seat. Everything was taken.
These young dentists
dedicated years of their lives--
Hey, Sartorio.
-I didn't see you.
-Hi, Barreda.
-Claudia, hello.
-How are you?
I'm good.
I haven't seen you
at the Jockey Club for a while.
Lots of mouths to fix.
And many to feed, too.
There's Ceci.
Okay, Ricardo,
can you get a little closer?
-Come on.
-Yes.
-There?
-No, Ricardo, get closer or you won't…
There you go. Perfect. Smile.
Come in.
Through that door.
Keep going.
Barreda.
Cáceres, this is crazy.
Yes, I can imagine.
Come, they gave us a room over here.
-Bring me his file, please.
-Yes, sir.
Who's that?
Débora is a young and talented lawyer
who works with me and who will assist us.
Okay, you do understand
you've been charged, right?
Charged for what?
What am I being accused of?
Okay, this will be a long process.
And to be honest with you,
it doesn't look good.
We're talking about the case
of an exemplary family.
But with a peculiarity:
they were living with a psychopath.
A murderer was living among us
and we didn't know.
So, the question is,
how can you go from being a role model
to slaughtering your family?
You don't understand. It was justice.
We can't keep wasting our time.
A judge needs to hear me.
Perfect. What will you say to him?
Go on, tell me.
You killed four people, Ricardo.
They were upper middle class.
A polite, educated man. A professional.
THE MONSTER OF LA PLATA
And suddenly, overnight,
he destroyed these women's lives.
A nefarious man. Society creates
these demons, and neighbors…
I'm not a monster.
If you want to look like the victim,
I need you to be precise.
You have to remember more details.
I'm a man who rebelled
in order to survive.
-To survive.
-Yes.
Why? What did they do to you?
I was their driver, their lackey.
If a button came off,
I had to sew it back on myself.
I paid for everything in our house,
and they would never appreciate it.
They would never thank me.
They had no mercy for me.
-That's not enough.
-Okay.
-You don't understand what I'm saying.
-You're the one who doesn't understand.
For the judges to hear us,
we need a strategy.
And a favorable public opinion.
Everyone hates you right now.
That needs to change.
Excuse me, ma'am.
Have you heard about the Barreda case?
Yes, such a horrible, terrible thing.
Those poor girls…
What happened was awful.
I can't believe it.
We're almost done, ten more minutes.
-No problem, sir.
-Thanks.
Your case is like a hot potato.
No one wants to take it.
I need to understand how a prestigious,
respectable dentist…
An important person.
Ends up making the worst decision.
You're going to kill me,
but I'm out of cold drinks.
Okay. Thank you very much.
See you later.
Can you turn the TV off?
Can't you see we're having a party?
Turn it off.
Mom, bring another tray, please.
-Congratulations, dentist!
-Hi.
-Very funny.
Thank you. They're beautiful.
-All good?
-Yes, all good.
Hello. Good evening.
Hi. Good evening.
Excuse me.
Can you take this outside?
I was like a ghost to them.
I didn't exist.
Only when someone had to…
We talked about that.
Let's go back to the abuse.
What did they do to you exactly?
Was there physical abuse?
No.
Okay, there was verbal abuse.
What did they say to you?
Everything.
"He doesn't understand.
He doesn't understand," they said.
-"The maid doesn't understand."
-They called you "maid"?
Yes. "Maid."
What else?
Do you think that's not enough?
We can't say you killed your family
because they called you "maid."
Do you understand?
We need something,
I don't know, more vulgar.
We need to be able to show that one day,
they provoked you and you lost your mind.
-I'm not crazy.
-I know.
Look, we need to create
a narrative that will save you.
They treated you so badly at home,
that one day, you snapped
and reacted in the worst way.
Understand?
So, what did they say to you?
That your dick was small,
that you couldn't get it up.
Coward?
Fucking old man? Gay?
-No, they never called me "gay."
-Okay, then what?
No, they didn't care
I was the man of the house.
The one with…
-I was just another vagina. That's it.
-What?
Yes.
I was the vagina of the house.
Not even a vagina.
A pussy.
That's what they called you?
Yes, say that.
Say they nicknamed me "Pussy."
He hasn't declared
at the District's Office…
-Cáceres.
-Mr. Cáceres.
A statement, please.
We weren't going to give
any statements, but…
Did Barreda feel guilty?
We weren't going to make any statements…
Look, Barreda, you're famous.
A family life full of abuses.
Believe it or not,
because I couldn't believe it myself,
Mr. Barreda went through hell
in his own house.
He was a victim of abuse, humiliation,
and horrible things
that pushed him to the limit.
-What did they call him?
-Why to the limit?
It's not the proper time to air this.
It's a vulgar word.
A way of calling
the female reproductive organ.
Could you be more specific?
"Pussy."
A new turn in the Barreda case.
It became known that the dentist
was nicknamed "Pussy."
-They called him "Pussy."
-"Pussy," yes.
That's what the women
in his house called him.
The defense attorney revealed the dentist
was a victim of subjugation for years.
He slept in the attic of his house.
He was harassed daily, and had to endure
a lot to continue being with them.
Barreda provided for the clan of women
so he wouldn't lose them.
Sources close to them revealed the women
had exorbitant expenses and whims,
and none of them worked.
Barreda was living a torment.
His house was hell.
Barreda is being transported
in this vehicle.
We are still reporting on this case.
-Barreda.
Barreda.
What can you say
to the people who came to support you?
Barreda!
Is it true that you have
a mental disorder?
Excuse me.
Was it an act of madness, Cáceres?
It was self-defense.
I have been neglected
by every member of my family
and subjected to all kinds of disrespect.
How were you humiliated and disrespected?
They ignored me. They insulted me.
They called me names
that I can't bring myself to repeat.
For example?
I think it's public knowledge.
Say it.
You have to say it
for the court to hear it.
Well, I'm sorry for what I'm about to…
My family called me "Pussy."
Give me money for the drinks.
Get money from my purse.
-Give me more.
-Can I have another glass, please?
Go and pay the guy.
The glasses are here.
-I can't reach.
-I'll help you.
-Thanks.
-You're welcome.
Did you see that damp stain?
They'll come to wallpaper this week.
Wallpaper is dirty and smells bad.
It won't solve the problem.
The stain will come out again.
The roof membrane has been fixed.
I called and paid for it.
When did you call?
I don't remember, you weren't here.
I don't know.
Can you help me with the drinks, please?
Did you know about this?
-About what?
-They're going to wallpaper the house.
This is my house.
-Half of it.
-Mom.
What? I'm just telling the truth.
Half is yours and you can do
whatever you want in your half.
I paid for the other half.
I can do what I want.
If I want to wallpaper it, I will.
Did you really need to say that?
What?
Why are you arguing with him?
We're still wallpapering it.
Tell me about your wife.
Why did you get separated?
Beba was very jealous.
She thought I had lovers everywhere.
And, because of my job,
I dealt with many women.
Why did you two make up?
I went looking for her.
We realized we couldn't live
without each other.
Ricardo…
Can we talk?
Open the door, please.
Ricardo…
Guys, come.
Can you help me with these? They're cold.
-I'll take them.
-Will you? Thanks.
We didn't go
to Cecilia's house very often.
And when we did, most of the time
her dad wasn't there.
According to other witnesses,
you and Cecilia were very close.
So, why wouldn't you go
to her house more often?
It was awkward.
He behaved in a weird way towards us.
In what way?
He…
He would stare at us.
He stared at you.
-You mean… in a lascivious way?
-Objection.
It's a suggestive question.
Sustained.
Counselor, please rephrase the question.
How did Mr. Barreda
look at you and your friends?
The way men look at women.
He looked at our legs.
Everywhere.
Other friends would say the same thing.
Cecilia and Adriana
would get very uncomfortable.
Why do you think that is?
They were affected by the things
he did outside his home.
Once, Cecilia, my boyfriend and I
were at the Jockey Club.
And he arrived at the pool with a woman.
We tried to distract Cecilia
so she wouldn't see him,
but Ceci wasn't stupid.
These things affected her.
That's why I think she didn't have
much of a relationship with her father.
Dad.
Dad, leave it. I'll pick it up later.
I'll wash this first.
What was your daily routine at home?
I worked all day in my office,
and when I finished,
I would do all the household chores.
They were very dirty.
And messy.
They left everything disorganized.
And they knew I was very clean,
very meticulous.
Sometimes, one of my daughters
would try to help me,
but they would stop them.
Who stopped them?
They wouldn't let them.
"Leave it like that.
Pussy can take care of it," they said.
But I was worried.
-But why, Grandma?
-Because I saw him drinking a lot.
I thought he was a minor. What a mess.
-He's like 25, Grandma.
-Okay, sweetie.
Then, he's a little man.
Not at all.
-He usually gets nervous, that's all.
-He's a funny little man.
Martín says he does it because he has
an inferiority complex.
-I'll read yours, Grandma.
-Sure, go ahead.
"Dynamic week, though rather tense.
Change is coming. You must be alert."
-I must be alert?
-Yes.
"You sometimes act with aggressiveness,
and he hates that."
-Who's "he"?
-The little man.
-The cardiologist.
-The little cardiologist.
The cardiologist isn't a little man.
He's very handsome.
They did everything behind my back.
And I had to pay for all their whims,
otherwise they would start insulting me,
and threatening me.
Your daughters, too?
Them, too.
It was all my mother-in-law's fault.
She was the mastermind
behind my family's ruin.
If the abuse was so great,
why didn't you leave?
Because I wanted to get my family back.
That's why I bought the house.
I wanted a family.
Thanks. No more questions.
As you can see, this is
the atmosphere outside the courthouse.
What do you think
about Barreda in this case?
I understand him. I went through the same
and I didn't speak up.
I know what it's like
for a woman to ruin you.
Go, Barreda! You're amazing!
We're with you!
Go, Pussy!
Look, there's some air in there.
You have to make sure it's neat
and that it matches the rest,
-because that will last forever.
-Yes
What's that stain? Is that dry?
Yes, it's dry.
You won't notice after we paint over it.
How long do you think it will take
for you to wallpaper everything?
A week, a week and a half.
I'll bring my team,
and we'll do it in no time.
Okay. Can you check this defective
electrical outlet before you leave?
-Yes, ma'am.
-Thank you.
We're not very handy.
Mom, can you hand me the towel?
Mom.
Thanks. The faucet won't close properly.
Leave it like that.
-Should I tell Dad?
-No, don't say anything.
Please set the table so we can eat
as soon as your sister is here.
Mom, you can't keep living this way.
Maybe you should talk to someone.
Why don't you call Lucía's mom?
A psychologist?
Rather, I should call a lawyer…
-Oh, Mom.
-No, I don't think so.
I'm not going to talk
about our private life.
To a stranger?
You're adults now, and you'll leave soon.
I'll sort things out.
How did the interview go?
What?
Fine. Well, who knows?
They haven't called me yet,
but Claudia said it takes a while.
-That's true.
-Is that faucet still leaking?
My head's about to explode.
-Hello.
-Hi.
-What did you do to your hair?
-It's a new look. You like it?
-Yes, I like it.
-Why did you do that?
-Mom.
-I did the same thing at your age.
Yes, you're a copycat.
-But it looks beautiful now.
-Yes.
This happens because you open
and close it all the time.
That's because it's a faucet, Ricardo.
Leave it, we already called a plumber.
Sure you did.
-Girls, can you set the table?
-Sure.
Ricardo, turn it off!
Dad, turn off the tap!
Turn it off, Ricardo!
I got it. I turned off the main valve.
Mom, you're soaked! And you too!
Quiet, he'll get upset.
Who cares? He can't fix anything!
Barreda.
Come in.
Jeez.
You look awful.
I feel pain here. In this area, yes.
-Sit. I'll be right back.
-Okay.
Someone cast the evil eye on you.
-What should I do?
-Cut the deck.
I'm not doing well.
I feel like an idiot, everything hurts.
Look.
Your house.
What?
You've been bewitched.
Look.
The real question is "who."
Who?
These women did something to you.
Search your house.
Search well. You'll be surprised.
Grab another one.
Introduce yourself to the court, please.
Tell us your name, occupation,
and relationship to the defendant.
My name is María de los Ángeles Arba,
but everyone has always called me Pirucha.
I'm a clairvoyant and Barreda's friend.
And his lover, right?
I'd say a very close friend.
But above all else,
I'm his spiritual guide.
Did Barreda tell you about his life?
He did.
And what he didn't tell me,
I would know anyway.
So, I imagine you knew
about his problems with the house.
His house? I don't get it.
Well, Barreda didn't want
to sell the house.
He wanted to keep it.
Didn't he mention that?
Objection. Suggestive question.
Sustained.
Counselor, please rephrase the question.
How did Barreda look to you lately?
Bad.
-Very bad.
-You mean aggressive.
-Objection.
-Counselor.
Please, tell us why he looked bad to you.
Barreda was going through…
a very confusing and a very dark time.
His body had been bewitched.
No more questions. Thank you.
-You're so handy.
-Thank you.
So embarrassing. We're making you work.
No, it's nothing.
I was taught when I was little.
Do you want more tea, guys?
You should eat something.
You didn't even touch the snacks.
-I'll try some.
-Yes.
I'm good. Thanks.
-Okay, I'll get you some.
-Thanks.
-So you know the Blancos's youngest son?
-Yes, Luisito.
Shorty!
Half a man, a tiny man. He's little.
-Yes.
-That's what they call him.
-"Sissy."
-Come on.
I don't like it when they call him that.
I don't like it either,
but compared to other men…
-Yes, he's effeminate.
-Yes.
Good afternoon.
Nice to meet you. I'm Gastón.
-Gastón?
-He's my boyfriend.
-Yes.
-Are you a plumber?
No, but I like to fix stuff.
Actually, I'm a PE teacher at Lincoln.
You're being modest.
He's in charge of the other teachers.
That's amazing.
-You also have a position at the club.
-Really? What club?
We're looking for a venue
for their wedding.
We saw several venues,
but didn't like any.
What about the Rotary?
-Okay, this is working fine now.
-You're an angel.
It's so nice to have a handyman.
Looks like you're the girl here.
What did you say?
I said,
looks like our girl here is leaving.
Well, not for a while, Baba.
As soon as Ceci gets
her residency training.
Is that so? And where will you move?
It depends on the hospital.
I hope it's here,
but it could be in the capital, too.
And that would be closer for us
to go see Sofi on the weekends.
Well…
-How old is your daughter?
-Six.
-She's in first grade.
-So nice.
-Yes, he has a daughter.
That's nice. So many news.
That's a nice toolbox you've got.
It has everything.
Excuse me.
Well, shall I put the kettle on?
Don't worry. It's not you.
He's like this with everyone.
I understand. Poor man.
I don't know what I'll do
when my daughter gets married and leaves.
Everything he said
about the abuse is a lie.
In fact,
when I got the call,
I immediately thought,
"That son of a bitch killed them."
Please, watch your language.
Go on, Counselor.
Who are you talking about?
Him.
Mr. Barreda?
Yes.
Let it be on the record that the witness
pointed at Ricardo Barreda.
In that moment, what made you so sure?
He was a manipulative man.
He'd make them feel bad all the time.
He wasn't a normal father.
I'm sure he had something against them.
To your understanding,
why do you think he killed them?
Because Ceci and I
were moving in together.
Because Martín and Adri
were getting married.
Because they were going to be happy.
Because he's a bastard.
That's all. Thanks.
No more questions.
-Be careful what you're about to say.
-I'd say either Gemini or Aquarius.
Come on!
Astrologers are all liars!
Am I right?
The first astrologers
were the Three Wise Men.
Yes, Melchior, Gaspar, and Balthasar.
The Three Wise Men, she says.
Party's over, I suppose.
No, it's fine.
Good night, Mom.
Good night.
-Ricardo, I went looking for you.
-Yes.
How much longer is this guy going to stay?
Is he going to live here now?
Stop that.
It's so hard to live like this.
-There's no communication between us.
-Us?
You mean us two? Us three?
How many is "us," Bebita?
I'm not going to argue with you.
Good night.
What happened now?
Do you know why you suffer?
You're still expecting him to change,
but he'll never change.
-Go ahead.
-Thanks.
Here you go, Doctor.
Thanks.
Bebi.
Yes?
Why don't you also try the shoes on?
It will look different.
-There's no need.
-Bebi, look at you.
Beautiful.
You look gorgeous.
I like it. I'd make it shorter, though.
-Just a little?
-No. Don't.
-Just a little bit.
-No, it's a wedding.
So?
-Do you like it?
-Yes, you look beautiful.
-I love it.
-You look gorgeous.
-Really?
-I love it.
-I love the embroidery.
-It's got something here.
It's too tight, Mom.
-Here? Silvi…
-Yes.
-Yes?
-Can you loosen it a little here?
-You can attach a hook.
-Yes.
You know what it's like to be
uncomfortable at your wedding?
Wasn't your dress comfortable, Mom?
It was so long ago. I don't remember.
It was Grandma's dress.
We did some alterations and that was it.
You have to be okay with it.
It's not just about a dress.
Happiness is built from the outside in.
-Right?
-I think it's the other way around.
I'll get something for you hair.
-Ready?
-Yes.
-Adri, you wanted a dress like this one.
-Yes, but it's uncomfortable.
-Ready?
-Yes.
Adriana, you wanted to get married
in a white dress.
You chose this dress.
I didn't know it'd fit like this.
Did you ever witness the abuse
the defendant claims to have endured?
Do you think it was real?
No, I don't think so.
They were a discreet family.
I never heard them yell at each other.
That being said,
would you say the word "Pussy"
is something that
could have been used frequently
by Mrs. Gladys McDonald,
the defendant's wife?
Beba? No way. She didn't curse.
Well, we've established
that there was no abuse,
and even if there was,
it doesn't justify the incident.
Thank you. No more questions.
Very well.
-Does the defense have any questions?
-Yes, thank you.
You said you knew Cecilia your whole life.
Would you say the Barredas were well-off?
I don't know the details,
but I think they were doing fine.
Did Cecilia Barreda ever mention what was
the source of income in her family?
No, we didn't talk about that.
But I'm sure you can deduce
who was paying the household bills.
Objection. That's not relevant.
This isn't a child support trial,
it's a multiple homicide trial.
Sustained. Get to the point, Counselor.
Okay.
How did Cecilia talk about her father?
With admiration, with disdain?
She didn't mention him much.
So, can we say that Mr. Ricardo Barreda
was always present when it came
to covering the family's expenses,
but he didn't receive
any affection in return?
-I don't know.
-No more questions. Thank you.
The witness may leave. Thank you.
Well, it seems to be going well.
Operating room number three.
Stay still.
The man I've known my whole life
would never even hurt a fly.
What changed in him, then?
His spirit.
Barreda was possessed by a demonic force
because those women
wanted to take everything for themselves,
but since they couldn't,
they turned to black magic to kill him.
What makes you so sure about that?
It's my gift, sir. My visions.
Sometimes, you see things,
but you don't talk about them.
And the facts.
He had all sorts of pain.
The darkness was taking over his body,
and I'm not surprised.
-Did Barreda believe in this stuff?
-Yes, of course.
Don't you?
He suffered.
Men are weaker.
With just one prick on a voodoo doll,
they come undone.
Like flan.
Voodoo doll?
Yes. A voodoo doll.
In fact, Barreda found it
and brought it to me.
Silence, please.
If I may.
Will you hand me that, please?
When you talk about a voodoo doll,
is this what you mean?
That's what it looked like in my visions.
What about the one Barreda found?
Like that one.
This is a pin cushion I bought
this morning at a notions store.
Probably Elena, who sewed once in a while,
had a similar one.
That's all. Thank you.
-What are you doing?
-Thank you, ma'am. You may leave.
Thank you. Goodbye.
Convert, Barreda. Only God can save you.
Ma'am, leave the room.
Ma'am, please.
Was he crazy? Was the abuse real?
I won't make any statements.
Did those women abuse him?
Everything's a lie, as I said.
That man's not crazy. Never was.
Apparently, there's complete commotion
on this day of hearings.
How's the man of the hour doing?
I can't believe what you're doing.
You're making me look like an idiot.
Whose side are you on?
You have two options.
You're either a nutjob or a piece of shit.
We either prove you're incompetent
and they send you to a psychiatric clinic,
or the fucking prosecutor
proves you planned everything
so you could keep the house.
And then you'll rot in prison.
You're the boss here.
But let me tell you something.
Five years from now, I can guarantee
you'll be out on the streets,
and that's all people will remember.
Listen to me.
You know what they were saying
on the radio on my way here?
What?
Barreda did what every Argentinian man
wishes he could do.
He rebelled against his mother-in-law.
Why do you think
so many people relate to you, Barreda?
-Go, Barreda!
-Go, Pussy!
Are you the prisoners' dentist?
Barreda, do abused men identify with you?
That's how Ricardo Barreda
appeared before court with his lawyer
on a new day of hearings,
in a trial that divides public opinion.
This is maybe the first time in history
that someone who confessed to killing
his daughters gets so much public support.
Silence, please.
Counselor.
A delirious man lives in a reality
that he himself created.
He will defend it by any means necessary.
What's his justification?
"They mistreated me,
they were mean," etcetera.
Okay, Doctor, just to be clear.
Are you saying Barreda wasn't
in his right mind when he did what he did?
What I mean is
Ricardo Barreda is suffering
from psychotic delusions of vindication.
In other words, he's crazy.
Exactly. He was crazy before the incident,
during the incident and now.
Thank you. No more questions.
-I'm not crazy.
-Silence, please.
Yes. May I approach the bench?
No, I should also be informed.
-You can approach, too.
-Please.
Given the expert's opinion,
and my client's condition,
I ask the magistrates to let him
leave the room during the next testimony.
-What do you think, Counselor?
-We could make an exception.
-You think so?
-As an exception. I have no objection.
-We will allow it as an exception.
-Thanks.
I appreciate it.
Débora, you may leave.
-I'm not going anywhere.
-Listen to me. Trust me.
We'll talk later.
Let's go. I'll explain.
-Barreda! A picture, please.
-Look over here, Barreda!
Listen to me, girl.
We shouldn't talk here.
-There's Barreda.
-Barreda!
-Here, Barreda!
-Where are they taking you?
-Look over here.
-Barreda.
Barreda, why did you leave the courtroom?
-Look over here!
Look here for a photo, Barreda!
What would you say
to your supporters, Barreda?
I'm with the patient in room number 23.
-Barreda?
-Yes.
-Okay.
-He's sleeping a lot, he barely moves.
That's normal.
He had a good night
and he's on the proper medication.
He had an inguinal hernia surgery, right?
I think with proper rest, he'll be fine.
You have to avoid-- Ma'am.
You must avoid
further injuries in that area…
Do you want me to make notes for you
so you get them with the discharge papers?
-Yes.
-Okay, we'll do that, then.
I'll call his daughters
to let them know he's fine.
There's a phone around the corner.
They didn't even visit me.
Can you believe it?
Of course, why would they come?
They're conspiring against you.
You were lucky this time, but…
Here, hide this. Don't let them find it.
They'll destroy you.
Holy Christ.
You have to leave that place.
I'm not going to get a divorce.
I told you so. It was obvious.
She's devastated.
How do you expect her to be?
She saw that woman there.
Sure. But I can't get into details now.
Hang on a second.
Rita agrees with me.
He is slowly making you sick.
You can't go on like this.
Hello.
Yes, I'll call you later
and we can talk some more, okay?
We're not going to let this slide.
Can you listen to me now?
How is this possible?
The expert you brought in
is burying me up to my neck,
and now you exclude me from my own trial.
It's normal in these cases.
-Sure, normal.
-Excuse me.
It's all good.
What's your boss doing now?
What did he tell the judges?
He's still insisting
on that "incompetent" bullshit.
Can't you see he's driving me mad?
-Who's the crazy one here?
-You're right.
You're not crazy, you're a murderer,
and you should go to jail.
Luckily, I'm not your lawyer,
and my boss hasn't lost a case
in five years.
If I were you, I'd follow his lead.
Sit down, please.
So you were playing dumb all along.
You act all virtuous, but you're a bitch.
-Got it.
-"Got it. Got it."
We're on a break. We're doing great.
Let's see if the prosecutor
can turn that one around.
You told me people would believe me.
They do. Didn't you read the papers?
You're famous.
I can hear the bullshit you said in there.
Things are different in there.
What did I tell you?
If you want to get your freedom
and your house back,
claiming you're incompetent is key.
-Do we agree?
-Yes.
Okay, because there's something else.
Cáceres… don't.
Yes. The order in which
the deaths happened.
You need to say that the last person
you shot was one of your daughters.
-At the police station, I said--
-I don't give a fuck. Listen to me.
If the last person you shot was your wife
or your mother-in-law, you're fucked.
You won't inherit anything.
Got it?
Okay. So, who did you shoot last?
-Cecilia.
-There.
Can you get us some coffee?
Well, the deed looks fine.
The property is under your name
and your husband's, right?
Yes.
We want to sell because one of the girls
is getting married,
and the other one's moving out.
It's a big house.
Too many square meters for us.
Sure.
Okay.
Can I take another look
around the ground floor?
Yes, of course.
-Yes?
-Yes.
Excuse me.
-May I go in?
-Yes, please.
If the buyer needs more space,
they can knock down this wall
and join the kitchen and the dining room.
They're doing that in Europe now.
It has potential.
Yes, it's really beautiful.
A great house for a family.
Okay, I'll call you in a few days
to give you an estimate.
And if we agree, we'll put it on sale.
-We'll publish the sale.
-Good afternoon.
Good afternoon.
-That's my husband.
-The gentleman is a real estate agent.
Sir, you have a beautiful property.
I promise we'll be able
to sell it quickly.
-Excuse me, I'll get my briefcase.
-Yes.
-Okay, thanks.
-You're welcome.
-Goodbye.
-I'll walk you out.
-Please.
-Bye.
Bye.
Great.
-Come, I need to tell you something.
-He liked it. He's gonna sell it.
Come in.
Excuse me.
Did they send you to talk to me?
No, I heard the music and came.
I was thinking the other day
about what kind of music
I want to play in my office.
Because playing ambient music
is a bit boring.
I don't know.
I play music to help my patients relax.
People think they're coming
to a torture chamber,
so I make them trust me.
Does it work?
Of course it works.
They're terrified when they come in,
but when they leave…
I'll take note of that.
Can I ask you a question?
Yes.
We have an extra room in the new house.
And I'm setting up my office there.
Something small just to start.
Remember you offered me your chair?
The old one, not this one.
It would really help me
because it's the most expensive thing.
Can I take it?
But for more invasive treatments,
a root canal, a removal,
never play opera.
Too dramatic. They'll never loosen up.
Sure.
Are you sure about this?
Are you really moving in
with that young man?
I mean, if you're sure,
go ahead, but…
Yes, I'm sure.
Okay.
I've had enough.
What?
You decide to ruin your life
by moving in with an older man
who has a daughter,
and you come here
asking for my chair to start working?
Why don't you ask him?
Why didn't you save up some money
like we all did?
Unless they already told you
they want to sell this house
and you thought you'd get money from that.
Did those two tell you that?
They didn't say anything.
Sunday is my last lunch here at home.
Gastón is coming.
You can be there, or not.
You're not taking these.
What's wrong?
He ruins every happy moment.
What did he say?
Tell me, what did he say?
Remember he offered me the old chair?
Yes.
Well, he won't give it to me now.
He says I'll ruin my life
with Gastón, and…
that he has a daughter, that the house--
That I should've saved up.
Ceci, don't pay attention to him.
I'm sick of it.
Listen to me. You're leaving.
You're going to start a new life,
and your own family, Ceci.
-That's beautiful.
-Yes.
-I don't want you to see me like this.
-No.
-I've seen you so many times like this.
-Yes, I know.
-I love you.
-Me too. I'll miss you.
Me too. So much.
He left.
Asshole. Fuck him.
Idiot.
-Let's go.
-Come with me, Barreda.
Go, Barreda!
Keep quiet!
-Go, Barreda,
-Silence!
Quiet down!
May I have some water, please?
Excuse me.
Thanks.
The prosecutor will now take over.
Go ahead.
Barreda, do you think these deaths
could have been avoided?
We all could've tried
to avoid what happened.
I'm talking about you.
Could you have avoided them?
-No, not me.
-Why?
Because of the humiliation,
the moral degradation,
the shame, and all those things…
No, I don't know.
I was already convinced.
It was either them or me.
Would you do it again?
Barreda, would you murder them again
if you could right now?
-Right now?
-Yes.
No, because that's…
-No.
-Because they're already dead.
No… No, that's…
Are you being serious, or are you joking?
How am I supposed to answer that?
However you want.
You have the right to answer.
-Please, mind your manners.
-However I want?
-Go on, answer. I think you understood.
-Yes, I understood perfectly.
-You said you're not sorry.
-Suggestive question.
Because that was a unique
and unrepeatable situation!
-Is that clear?
-So you'd do it again.
Let's have some order.
I was able to have a harmonious dialogue
with the judges, but not with you.
No more questions.
After you.
-Good evening.
Through that door over there.
It's starting.
Thanks.
This is unbelievable.
-Isn't that Barreda?
-No, it can't be.
Excuse me.
Sorry.
Yes, it's him.
No, Mom.
Stay here.
Son of a bitch.
Don't move.
Here. Take it.
Ricardo.
It's over.
After Cecilia and Adriana move out,
we're getting a divorce.
I can't take it anymore.
Why did you have to bring that woman?
I believed you.
I convinced myself time and time again
that things would get better.
But it's useless. You don't care.
You crossed the line today.
I'm going to see a lawyer.
BARREDA IS INNOCENT
Today, Barreda will declare in front
of the judges for the last time.
The anticipation is huge
to hear him recount
all the details of the day of the crime.
By explaining
what really happened that day,
Barreda will be closer to his freedom.
Now we just need to wait
for the judges' decision.
Barreda, do you remember
how that Sunday started?
You have reached Dr. Barreda's office.
No, it'll always be sour
if you use that one.
-…opening hours, Monday to Friday…
-Mom.
Add some sugar.
Or leave a message after the beep. Thanks.
-Hello.
-Good morning, honey.
Good morning, Grandma.
It's me, Martín.
I wanted to know if I should pick you up.
-Hi, baby, how are you?
-Hi, honey, all good?
All good.
I'm glad. Will you have lunch there
or what will you do?
I'm having lunch here.
But we'll go to the movies
afterwards, right?
Yes, maybe. But later.
It's so sunny today.
Barreda, was there a reason
you picked that Sunday?
No.
I didn't know when I was going to do it.
Since I had my hernia surgery,
I'd been having this horrible thought
that was getting bigger every day.
It was inevitable.
Last breakfast
for the spoiled one in the house.
You brought me breakfast, Baba! So nice!
-What are you looking at?
-Look what I found.
We were so little.
-So little.
-Right?
Do you remember what the trigger was?
When did you think
that was the right moment?
I was listening to that.
We were all listening to that.
My head's exploding.
Ricardo.
Why don't you go prune the vine?
You have time today.
"Narrow or reduced."
Is this guy coming for lunch?
-Narrow, reduced…
-"Slim"? I'll put this over here.
Okay.
No, it doesn't fit.
Yes, he's coming. His name is Gastón.
-I don't like that guy.
-Don't start, it's Sunday.
"Tight." Of course, I'm so dumb.
And Cecilia?
Packing up since 6:00 a.m.
She can continue later.
Tell her to come down.
-What for?
-For breakfast.
She already had breakfast.
Why don't you occupy yourself
with something?
Cecilia!
-Cecilia!
-Ricardo.
What are you doing?
I'll kill you if you bother her.
Go take care of the vine.
I'll clean the front porch.
It's so dirty that it's embarrassing.
Do whatever you want.
If you want to clean all day like a maid,
go ahead. Just don't bother her.
My wife told me…
that if I bothered my daughter,
she'd kill me.
And what did you say?
Nothing.
I just want to have breakfast in peace.
Fine.
It doesn't matter. What do you want?
I don't get it.
The vine is overgrown.
We have to go up there and fix the guide.
But I can't, my arms get tired.
You don't give a damn
if I fall and smash my head.
Hi? Honey, did something happen?
Oh, no. Poor thing.
What's her temperature?
Oh, I'm sorry.
No, it's fine. We'll do it another day.
What time are the movers coming tomorrow?
Perfect.
Sure. I'll tell Mom.
Me too. Bye.
What happened? Who were you talking to?
It was Gastón. He won't be able to come.
His daughter has a fever.
Better. I mean,
I'm sorry for the girl, but…
-Some other time will be better.
-Yes.
-Go. Finish packing.
-Okay.
You too, go do whatever you have to do.
Don't look at me like that.
Then, she said to me,
"Go clean the house.
That's all you're good at, Pussy."
What happened then?
I said, "Pussy will go fix the vine,
since that's what you all want."
So, I went to get the hand pruners,
and I found the shotgun in the basement.
And I felt like…
Like a force compelling me to pick it up.
So I picked it up,
went to the kitchen and shot.
And then?
My mother-in-law was coming down
from the second floor…
and…
I shot her.
In your first statement to the police,
you said you shot your daughter first,
and your mother-in-law last.
I don't know. I'm not sure.
"Mythological figure who used
a thread to get out of a labyrinth."
Mom!
Ceci.
-Did you hear that?
-What?
-Stay here.
How can a family man,
a prestigious dentist,
be capable of carrying out
such a bloodbath?
That's what the whole country
was wondering during this trial.
Ricardo Barreda suffers
from a serious delusional disorder.
He is delirious.
He's absolutely convinced
that what happened had to happen,
as if a higher deterministic force
guided his actions.
Delirium? Abuse?
None of that could be proved,
because none of it was real.
This quadruple murder
was a calculated violent incident.
He chose that day because it was the last
day the four of them were together.
He fabricated an alibi.
First, I went to the zoo.
The giraffe is my favorite animal.
He kept the admission ticket as evidence.
He planned dates to have witnesses
to every step he took that day.
He made a reservation in one of the most
popular pizza restaurants in La Plata.
He meticulously chose the people
who would help him get rid of the evidence
and the most remote place to do it
without being seen.
Everything was premeditated.
Some robbers broke into my house.
There are four bodies.
Having an alibi, even to convince oneself,
is typical in a transient delirium.
Sure, that's why he confessed
that same day.
Look, you can be crazy
and fabricate an alibi.
-Is that correct?
-Yes, that's correct.
This crime was marked by cruelty,
by premeditation,
and by greed.
From the very beginning,
Barreda showed a composed coldness.
His actions are typical of someone
who deeply hates the women in his family.
It would be more reassuring
if only crazy people were murderers,
but it's not like that.
Barreda has his own ethics, his own rules.
And by these rules, he killed four women.
Society already understood
that Barreda was driven crazy.
He needs to be treated.
I ask the judges to sentence
Mr. Ricardo Barreda to life sentence.
I ask the judges
to declare him incompetent.
That's what the people are asking.
Justice for this man.
Barreda murdered his entire family.
If he is not convicted,
what message are we sending to society?
This afternoon, the court sentenced
Ricardo Barreda to life imprisonment.
The ruling, that had…
How do you feel
about the sentence, Barreda?
…voting in favor of criminal liability.
He's coming out.
You're my idol!
Did the sentence surprise you?
-Barreda!
-Son of a bitch!
Here, take it!
You'll die in prison.
What do you think about that?
Murderer!
-Murderer!
-You're great!
You're amazing, Barreda!
Piece of shit!
You're my idol, Pussy!
After spending only 17 years in prison,
Ricardo Barreda got his freedom back.
He remarried and died at age 84.
Even today, he's admired
with a mix of devotion and irony.
At the time of their deaths, Elena Arreche
was 86, Gladys McDonald, 56,
Cecilia Barreda, 26,
and Adriana Barreda, 24.
Very little was known about them,
and their portrayal in this film
is based on public statements
of those who knew them.
Subtitle translation by MC Irazoqui